<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Sihao Sun</title>
    <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://SihaoSun.github.io/images/icon_hu6c1b14bc8ff89c2ed4ecac6b87cb96ac_156507_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accurate Aerial Manipulation under Uncertainties</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/accurateam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/accurateam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike mobile robots on the ground, air manipulators are based on a flying platform that can easily suffer from external forces and torque disturbances from the environment, such as wind and unknown payloads. This project aims to improve the accuracy of air manipulators through both hardware design and algorithm improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Aerial Manipulations of Cable-Suepended Loads</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/camls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/camls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drones have limited load capacities, and developing heavy-lifting drones is costly. Using multiple drones to collaboratively lift a load offers theoretically unlimited load capacities, yet it offers substantial challenges in coordination, planning, estimation, and control. This project aims at algorithmic development to enable agile, robust, and decentralized collaboration to enable collaborative aerial manipulation of a cable-suspended load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, we have developed a centralized algorithm, recently published in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/stoken/author-tokens/ST-3015/full&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Science Robotics&lt;/a&gt;. It considers the quadrotors-cables-load system as a whole, and solves the kinodynamic motion planning problem online to generate receding horizon reference trajectories for all quadrotors. The trajectories are subsequently followed by onboard INDI (incremental nonlinear dynamic inversion) controllers to compensate for cable tensions and other external disturbances. Notably, no additional sensors are required to be mounted on the load; instead, the load poses are estimated through quadrotor state estimates. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sihaosun.github.io/ScienceRoboticsCAMLs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Here is the link to the paper&amp;rsquo;s project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 10px; flex-wrap: wrap; justify-content: center; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: -10px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure style=&#34;width: 100%; text-align: center; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video autoplay loop muted playsinline width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;source src=&#34;flythrough.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
      Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt; Obstacle avoidance maneuver with the centralized method (Science Robotics)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve further explored two paths towards decentralized cooperative aerial manipulation. Decentralized means that the algorithms are executed fully onboard each quadrotor, without a centralized coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first attempt was recently accepted by IEEE MRS 2025. This work, entitled &amp;ldquo;Decentralized Real-Time Planning for Multi-UAV Cooperative Manipulation via Imitation Learning&amp;rdquo; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.17143&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to the paper&lt;/a&gt;), leverages imitation learning to train student policies for each quadrotor (with only partial observability, namely states of each quadrotor itself) by learning the centralized teacher policy (the abovementioned centralized planner). The same as the teacher, the student policy also generates receding horizon reference trajectories for each quadrotor. To ensure smoothness, we leverage Physics-informed neural networks (PINNs) as the architecture of the student policy. The training leverages the DAgger (Dataset Aggregation) algorithm. This approach has shown decent trajectory tracking performance and even generalizability beyond the training trajectories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second attempt was recently presented at CoRL 2025, entitled &amp;ldquo;Decentralized Aerial Manipulation of a Cable-Suspended Load Using Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning&amp;rdquo; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://autonomousrobots.nl/paper_websites/aerial-manipulation-marl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to the project&lt;/a&gt;). In this work, we explored the capability of multi-agent reinforcement learning (MA-PPO). We trained the PPO in the simulation environment with a centralized critic and decentralized actors. The policy is deployed onboard each quadrotor, taking its own states and the load states as observations. The action space is selected as accelerations and angular rates, then executed by onboard INDI controllers. In addition to similar setpoint tracking performance compared to the centralized method, it also &amp;ldquo;emerges&amp;rdquo; fault-tolerance. When one quadrotor fails in flight, the remaining quadrotors can still control the remaining controllable DoFs of the load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 10px; flex-wrap: wrap; justify-content: center; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: -10px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure style=&#34;width: 100%; text-align: center; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video autoplay loop muted playsinline width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;source src=&#34;failure_agent.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
      Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt; Stable and controllable flight after failure of one quadrotor (CoRL 2025)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Flight Control for Drones</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotoragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotoragile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many drones, such as quadrotors, are highly agile compared with other robotic/aerospace systems. However, their agility is not fully exploited, owning to the immaturity of flight algorithms. This project aims at further excavating the potential of drones to achieve their maximum agility, which is highly beneficial for time-critical missions such as search and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we have made a thorough 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpg.ifi.uzh.ch/docs/Arxiv21_MPC_Sun.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comparative study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the two most promising control approaches for agile drone flights: the differential-flatness-based controller (sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s referred to as the geometric control), and the nonlinear model predictive control. This study shows that both methods have the ability to track agile trajectories with 20m/s top speed and 5g acceleration. But the nonlinear model predictive control shows better performance when tracking many dynamically infeasible trajectories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also propose a 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpg.ifi.uzh.ch/docs/Arxiv21_MPCC_Romero.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nonlinear model predictive contouring controller (MPCC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for agile drone flights. Unlike the above two state-of-the-art methods, this control approach does not need an off-line generated time-optimal trajectory encoding full states of a quadrotor. Instead, it can follow arbitrary 3D paths in a near-time-optimal manner. These 3D paths can be splines, or time-optimal trajectories computed using a reduced model, which can be effectively generated online to be adaptive against environmental uncertainties. Thanks to this property, our method achieves a decent trade-off between robustness and performance during agile flights in cluttered environments. (Check our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/mHDQcckqdg4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model uncertainties, especially from complex aerodynamic effects, are another major threat to flying safety and degrade the performance in agile flights. For this, we proposed a nonlinear model predictive control framework combining the L1 adaptive control 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2109.04210.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(L1-NMPC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Extensive flight experiments demonstrate that the proposed method has high robustness against different types of model uncertainties, including mismatch in the inertial properties, slosh payload (like a beer!), and complex aerodynamic effects. (Check our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8oB1rG5iYc4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- effectively reduce the effort of generating a time-optimal trajectory that is normally computationaly untractable on an embbedded computer.  --&gt;
&lt;!-- As the most commonly used and simplest multi-rotor drones, quadrotors are
especially vulnerable to rotor failures because they lack rotor redundancy. This project aims at introducing novel flight control methods to mitigate the consequence of in-flight motor failures, which rarely happens but is still a big safety threat after large scale deployment of drones in the future.

To be specific, the project leverages incremental nonlinear dynamic inversion (INDI) control method, to stabilize and control a quadrotor with failure of a [**single rotor**](/publication/highspeedral/) or [**two opposing rotors**](/publication/incrementalnonlinear/), under significant aerodynamic disturbances. These strong aerodynamic effects are dominant in high-speed flight, or windy conditions. Thanks to the robustness of the INDI controller, the damaged quadrotor maintains controllable in spite of these aeordynamic disturbances.

We have validated the proposed controllers in a large scale wind tunnel, named [**Open Jet Facility**](https://www.tudelft.nl/lr/organisatie/afdelingen/aerodynamics-wind-energy-flight-performance-and-propulsion/facilities/low-speed-wind-tunnels/open-jet-facility/) at TU Delft. Despite a complete loss of one or two propellers, the tested quadrotor can maintain high-speed flight. In addition to validating the controller, these wind tunnel flight tests have produced valuable data for identifying [**aerodynamic models**](/project/quadrotormodeling) of a quadrotor, in both nominal and damaged conditions.

Another focus of the research aims at recovering the damaged quadrotor after motor failure. When a motor failure is detected, a quadrotor might have been entered a detrimental flight condition, such as an upside-down orientation, where the drone can hardly recover to stable flights using the state-of-art methods.
Therefore, we have developed an [**upset recovery controller**](/publication/upsetrecovery/), using a novel control allocation approach. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadrotor Fault Tolerant Flight Control</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotorftc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotorftc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the most commonly used and simplest multi-rotor drones, quadrotors are
especially vulnerable to rotor failures because they lack rotor redundancy. This project aims to introduce novel flight control methods to mitigate the consequence of in-flight motor failures, which rarely happen but are still a big safety threat after large-scale deployment of drones in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be specific, the project leverages the incremental nonlinear dynamic inversion (INDI) control method, to stabilize and control a quadrotor with failure of a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/highspeedral/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;single rotor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/incrementalnonlinear/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;two opposing rotors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, under significant aerodynamic disturbances. These strong aerodynamic effects are dominant in high-speed flight, or windy conditions. Thanks to the robustness of the INDI controller, the damaged quadrotor maintains controllable in spite of these aeordynamic disturbances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have validated the proposed controllers in a large-scale wind tunnel, named 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tudelft.nl/lr/organisatie/afdelingen/aerodynamics-wind-energy-flight-performance-and-propulsion/facilities/low-speed-wind-tunnels/open-jet-facility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Jet Facility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at TU Delft. Despite a complete loss of one or two propellers, the tested quadrotor can maintain high-speed flight. In addition to validating the controller, these wind tunnel flight tests have produced valuable data for identifying 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotormodeling&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aerodynamic models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of a quadrotor, in both nominal and damaged conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another focus of the research aims at recovering the damaged quadrotor after motor failure. When a motor failure is detected, a quadrotor might have entered a detrimental flight condition, such as an upside-down orientation, where the drone can hardly recover to stable flights using the state-of-art methods.
Therefore, we have developed an 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/upsetrecovery/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;upset recovery controller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, using a novel control allocation approach. We have explored the performance of using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/mpc_ftc&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nonlienar model predictive controller (NMPC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the upset recovery task. The fail-safe performance is mind-blowing. It is able to recover the quadrotor after motor failure not only from extreme orientations, but also from agile flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above research, all rely on external sensors to provide reliable state estimates of the damaged quadrotor. This is a strong assumption in real-world scenarios where motion capture systems are not available and GPS signals can be degraded. For this reason, we have explored using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/visionftc&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onboard vision sensors to provide a full-state estimation of the drone with motor failures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The high-speed yaw motion makes it challenging to use a vision-based estimator as it brings motion blur. Hence we have conducted a research project to explore the potential of using standard frame-based cameras and event-based cameras on quadrotor fail-safe tasks. This work has been awarded a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ieee-ras.org/publications/ra-l/ra-l-paper-awards&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Paper Award from IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerodynamic Modeling Identification for Multi-Rotor Drones</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotormodeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotormodeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aerodynamic effects of a multi-rotor drone are complicated. Although most of the time, a multi-rotor drone operates at a near-hovering condition where these aerodynamic effects are negligible, a high-speed applicable aerodynamic model is &amp;ldquo;always&amp;rdquo; welcomed for analyzing drone performance, designing agile flight tractories, and boosting controller performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research project aims at developing aerodynamic models of a quadrotor using system identification approaches. To this end, we have conducted flight tests of a quadrotor in a large scale wind tunnel, namely Open Jet Facility at TU Delft. As a first research outcome, we have obtained a high-speed applicable 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/grayboxmodel/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gray-box model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; capturing dominant aerodynamic effects (such as blade-flapping, thrust variation) as well as minor effects (e.g., rotor-body wake interactions, aerodynamic moments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After designing some novel 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/quadrotorftc/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fault-tolerant flight controllers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we have conducted a wind tunnel flight test of a high-speed spinning quadrotor with the complete failure of one or two rotors. Using these flight data, we have identified a more generalized 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://SihaoSun.github.io/publication/aerodynamicmodel/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aerodynamic force/moment model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, with very few parameters. This model can be either applied to a quadrotor without failure or with the complete loss of a propeller.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Efficiency Air Cargo Design</title>
      <link>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/aircargo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SihaoSun.github.io/project/aircargo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-Efficiency Air Cargo Design Challenge is the most competitive and challenging event in the Chinese Aeromodelling Design Championship. In this competition, the participants need to design an unmanned aircraft to carry as much payload as possible, while the maximum empty weight of the aircraft is limited to 3kg. In addition, it needs to drop the load (i.e., water bags) onto a target area with sufficient accuracy. Each team’s final score is calculated according to the payload carried and the number of successful “takeoff-drop-landing” cycles within 9 minutes. Hence, it poses high demands on the aircraft design to achieve high aerodynamic and structural efficiency, and decent dynamic characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, as a senior bachelor student, I led a group of 50 students from the faculty of aerospace engineering, electrical engineering, and automation. We designed an aircraft with a wingspan of 4 meters, made up of multiple composite materials, and optimized aerodynamics. We used opensourced and comercial tools to optimize our structral and aerodynamic design, such as XFoil and ANSYS Fluent. Several special designs are also developed and deployed in the competition, such as an all-flying tail, a self-starting engine, and an all-in-one flap-spoiler. The team finally won the championship, and led the competition for three consecutive years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
